alberta.ca 2019-12-19

# Privacy | Alberta.ca

## Collection of information

All information is collected in compliance with section 33 (c) of the _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act_.

When you visit this site, our web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation and evaluation of the site. This information is not used to identify individuals who come to the site, nor is it disclosed to other public bodies or individuals.

The information that's collected identifies the following:

  * the page from which you arrived
  * the date and time of your page request
  * the IP address your computer is using to receive information
  * the type and version of your browser
  * the name and size of the file you request

The FOIP Act provides access to information held by public bodies which is not available by other means, and allows individuals to request correction of their own personal information that a public body holds, this is called a FOIP request. The [FOIP request form](https://eservices.alberta.ca/foip-request.html) is available through the MyAlberta eServices page. For more information see the Protection of Privacy to locate a FOIP office to determine if the ministry you are interested in has any public records are available.

## Personal information

The only information we may use to identify you is the information you give voluntarily. For example, when you sign up for email updates of government announcements, you will be asked to provide your email address.

This personal information is disclosed only to the authorized personnel who use it to process and respond to your request.

While the personal information you send is secure once it reaches the government server, it may not be secure in transit between your computer and ours. For more information about any of the policies described above, please contact:

Director, Digital Communications  
Email: [internetcomm@gov.ab.ca](mailto:internetcomm@gov.ab.ca?subject=GOA%20Privacy%20statement)

## Cookies

When you visit a website it may deposit a piece of data, called a web cookie, with the temporary web browser files on your computer.

If you wish, you can change the settings on your web browser to deny cookies, or to warn you when a site is about to deposit cookies on your hard drive.

Government of Alberta websites use cookies to collect anonymous statistical information such as browser type, screen size, traffic patterns and pages visited. This information helps us provide you with better service. We do not store personal information in cookies, nor do we collect personal information from you without your knowledge, as you browse the site.

### Cookies from third party applications

This site uses a number of third party products. Read their privacy statements to find out how they track and use your information:

## Security

The Government of Alberta's computer system uses software to monitor unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or damage the service we provide. No attempt is made to identify users or their usage patterns except during law enforcement investigations.
  *[FOIP]: Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy
